edcentretralee.ie 2019-12-19

# Education Centre Tralee | Teacher CPD - Privacy Policy

THE EDUCATION CENTRE, TRALEE

### Our Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy statement is effective as and from 25th May 2018

Your privacy is important to The Education Centre, Tralee and maintaining your trust is important to us.  We are fully committed to keeping your personal information safe.  We will comply with the terms of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and all other relevant data protection legislation.  If we ask another organisation to provide a service for us, we will ensure that they are also in compliance. This Privacy Policy is intended to provide you with information about personally identifiable information we collect about you and how that personal information is used and shared.

Any reference to the “Service” within this Privacy Policy includes “The Education Centre, Tralee, (“The Education Centre, Tralee”, “we” or “us”), our website at [https://www.edcentretralee.ie](https://www.edcentretralee.ie/) (the “Site”), other services provided by us and on which a link to this Privacy Policy is displayed and all other communications with individuals through written or oral means such as email or phone (collectively, together with the Site, our “Service”).  This Privacy Policy (“Policy”) describes the information that we gather on or through the Service, how we use and disclose such information and the steps we take to protect such information. By visiting the Site, or by using the Service (registering and booking CPD courses/ events/any related training & education provisions), you accept the privacy practices described in this Policy.

The Education Centre, Tralee will intermittently update this Privacy Policy.  If we make changes, we will notify you prior to the changes taking effect by posting a notice on our website and where appropriate, sending you a notification.  By continuing to use our “Service” after such revisions are in effect, you accept and agree to the revisions.

The Education Centre, Tralee values your opinions.  Should you have any questions in relation to our Privacy Policy, please contact us at [edcentretralee@eircom.net](mailto:edcentretralee@eircom.net)

### Data Controller

The Education Centre, Tralee of Dromtacker, Tralee, County Kerry V92 HK52, Ireland is the data controller of the personal data you provide to us.  We can be contacted by email at [edcentretralee@eircom.net](mailto:edcentretralee@eircom.net) or by phone on (066)7195000.

### Data Protection Officer

We have appointed an internal Data Protection Officer (DPO) for you to contact if you have any questions regarding our Privacy Policy and our privacy practices.  Whilst we have appointed a DPO, the Administration Office team will be your initial point of contact for all data protection inquiries. They can be reached by email at [edcentretralee@eircom.net](mailto:edcentretralee@eircom.net) or by phone at (066) 7195000.

**Information We Collect**

We collect information about you, including personal information, as you use our services and interact with us.

**How We Use Your Information**

When you register as a “User” on The Education Centre, Tralee “Site”, “Service”, we collect personally identifiable information about you i.e. your profile (your name, surname, teaching council number, mobile/telephone number, email address, school name, school roll number, school email address, school telephone number) and/or similar.  We will collect your profile solely to provide access to your registration area, to generate and view your record of participation in our CPD / Training & Education provisions in conjunction with maintaining your attendance and certification record(s). We will not use your collected data for any other purpose or to send you any commercial advertisements.

**How We Share Your Information**

We will not share, rent or sell your personally identifiable information to others.  We may store personal information in locations outside the direct control of the Education Centre, Tralee e.g. on servers or databases provided by our hosting provider.  Management, security and integrity of data storage are under the direct responsibility of our hosting provider company and are governed by the privacy policy of the organisation providing the hosting service. 

**Storage and Processing**

The information we collect about you through the Education Centre, Tralee may be stored and processed in Europe by our third-party hosting provider.  The management, security and integrity of data storage are the direct responsibility of our hosting provider and are governed by the privacy policy of those hosting organisations.

**How We Protect Your Information**

The Education Centre, Tralee is concerned with protecting your privacy and data but we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or guarantee that your information on the Education Centre, Tralee “Site” “Service” may not be accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed by breach of any of our Business standard physical, technical or managerial safeguards.  When you enter sensitive information (such as log in credentials) on our registration or order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). No method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. We use external third-party payment processors such as PayPal and Stripe to process your payment when you book a course.  These third-party payment processors do not retain share, store or use personally identifiable information for any other purposes.  Your interactions with these external payment processing organisations are governed by their own privacy policies.

**Access and Retention of Data Controlled by Our Users**

For existing/current Education Centre, Tralee Users, you can review, correct, or update your current profile by logging into your profile e.g. to update your password.  We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you with our services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements.  If you wish to delete or export your account data, please contact us directly at [edcentretralee@eircom.net](mailto:edcentretralee@eircom.net)

**Cookies and Tracking Technologies – how we use Cookies**

We use cookies for the best browsing experience.  Cookies are very small text files that are stored on your computer when you visit websites.  We use technical cookies to help identify your device so we can tailor your user experience, track your session, course/event booking and remember where you are in the booking process.  You can disable any cookies already stored on your computer but these may stop our website from functioning properly. The following is strictly necessary in the operation of our website.

The Education Centre, Tralee “Site” will:

  * Remember what courses you are applying for (e.g. when logged in and booking a course)

  * Remember where you are in the booking process

  * Remember that you are logged in and that your session is secure.  You need to be logged in to complete a booking.

Functional Cookies are not Strictly Necessary, but are required to provide you with the best user experience and also to tell us which pages you find most interesting (anonymously).

The Education Centre, Tralee “Site” will:

  * Track the pages you visit via Google Analytics

  * Third-Party Cookies

This “Site” will not share any personal information or directly use third parties cookies.

**Social Media Widgets / Analytics**

Our Site may include social media features, such as the Facebook Like button and other widgets, which run on our Site.  These features may collect your IP address, identify which page you are visiting on our Site and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third-party or hosted directly on our Site.  Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the organisations providing them. Our website uses Google analytics, which collects information about your session whilst you interact with our website. Analytics will collect your IP address, your location and identify the page you are visiting on our Site.  It will set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the organisation providing them. 

**The Education Centre, Tralee CPD training courses (Contract)**

The Education Centre, Tralee provides Continuing Professional Development (CPD)/ Training & Education services for Primary and Post Primary Teachers.  To register/enrol/ and book/pay for our training courses/ programmes and CPD services you will, in the first instance, need to be a registered “User” on our website.  By enrolling/booking on a CPD training course/programme with us, you agree that your personal information is being processed in the manner described in this Privacy Policy.

We use the personal information (your profile) which you provide to us to administer and manage these CPD/ Training & Education services including registration, billing, collection of fees and charges.  We will collect your profile solely to provide access to your registration area, to generate and view your record of participation in our CPD/ Training & Education services and to maintain your course attendance and certification(s) records.  We will use the email address you provide for the purpose of distributing any training materials related to your CPD/ Training & Education undertaking(s) and to keep you informed. We may also collect and store information provided by you to consider your CPD requirements i.e. needs analysis for the purpose of designing course content and/or evaluating the quality of our provision /service to you.

Your personal information may be shared with our third-party Training & Education partners, professional development support personnel, trainers, facilitators, tutors and various education bodies and agencies under the remit of the Department of Education and Skills (DES) or other relevant Government agencies and organisations.  If your CPD / Training & Education provision is delivered by an external educational body, we will share your personal data with that external educational body only as applicable and appropriate.

**To pay for CPD courses you have requested from us (Contract)**

When you book a course with us, our third-party payment processors such as PayPal and/or Stripe (Payment Card Industry compliant payment providers) will collect your payment information.  Your interaction with third-party payment processors is governed by the privacy policy of those processors.  We will not share by any manner or means your personal data with PayPal and Stripe payment gateways.  You are redirected from The Education Centre, Tralee website to these external websites and the interaction with these external websites is governed by the privacy policy of those organisations.

**To receive our Newsletter communications (Consent – Opt in)**

With your permission, The Education Centre, Tralee intermittently sends our Newsletter and information emails about CPD/Training & Education provisions to the email address you have provided.  You may at any time choose not to receive our Newsletter communications by following the unsubscribe instructions included at the end of each email communication.  Any existing registrant/User can also unsubscribe by logging in and editing his/her profile.

In line with the new data protection regulations, GDPR, the Education Centre, Tralee will give existing registrants (Users) the opportunity to click on a link to “opt in” to subscribe to the Newsletter, therefore agreeing to continue receiving the Newsletter communication.  Any existing registrant/User that does not use the link to “opt in” will automatically be removed and deleted from the Newsletter database.  Registrants who have not booked a CPD/Training & Education provision within the last four years or more will also be automatically deleted and removed from the Education Centre, Tralee website database.

**In communication with us (Legitimate Interest)**

If you correspond with us, we will collect information such as your name, address, phone number and email address and any other personal information contained within the communication and use it to respond to your inquiry.  We process this information in pursuit of our legitimate interests i.e. providing continuing personal and professional development for teachers and school communities and implementing our statutory remit.

**If you attend one of our CPD /Training & Education provisions (e.g. courses, programmes, other educational events) (Contract)**

The Education Centre, Tralee organises a comprehensive CPD /Training & Education programme during the year.  If you register for one of these training courses/programmes/ events we will collect your name and contact information and in some contexts, your address and payment details.  We use this information to facilitate your registration, process your payment and provide you with the associated information and services. In some circumstances, we take photographs or make video recordings of these events.  We will always inform you if the provision is being photographed /recorded so that you can choose not to participate.

**When you provide services to us (Contract)**

If you provide professional services to the Education Centre, Tralee and you provide your personal information, which typically includes your contact information, address, phone number, VAT registration number and possibly your banking information, we will process this information so that we can administer, manage and pay for the relevant services you provide and as per the terms and conditions of our contract.
